# Santiago Diaz

## Software Developer

A humble, tenacious problem solver and constant learner with 2+ years of full-stack software development experience. Seeking to reenter software development as a full-stack Web developer in a remote friendly (work from anywhere) capacity. Legally authorized to work in Canada and Colombia.



xanti.diazl@icloud.com

(647) 479-8933



Colombia

in linkedin.com/in/santi-diaz



github.com/santidiazl



## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Co-founder

Código Lab (Coding Bootcamp)

03/2020 - 10/2021 Colombia

- Co-founded Código Lab, a Web development bootcamp based in Colombia that offered a 12-week, full-time program, to address Colombia's tech talent shortage.
- Responsibilities included business dev, marketing, operations, building and maintaining our React website, maintaining financial/accounting records as well as mentoring/coaching our students.
- Developed a robust marketing funnel and lead nurturing with free content and tutorials. Increased Website traffic through technical SEO and content marketing in the form of blog posts containing primary data generated by Python scripts I created to scrape a Colombian job board.
- Successfully completed 2 pilot classes totaling 7 students, contributing positively to their careers.

#### **Implementation Consultant**

Cority Software 🗷

10/2016 - 02/2020 Toronto, ON / Remote

Cority is a SaaS platform large enterprises use for managing their EHSQ requirements and workflows.

- Responsible for getting the complex, highly-configurable software live for new clients.
- Conducted requirements workshops with clients to map the platform's workflows to their processes and configured the platform in iterative cycles until it passed user acceptance testing.
- Collaborated with the engineering and product teams to address any "show-stopping" gaps in the platform's functionality identified during project, ensuring their proper follow-up and resolution.
- Achieved a 100% project implementation success rate, deploying the platform for over 15 clients.

#### MBA Summer Intern

Scotiabank, Global Risk Management

05/2015 - 09/2015 Toronto, ON

- Sole intern selected among pool of MBA candidates from various Toronto business schools to facilitate the rollout and post-implementation review of two major initiatives.
- Supported and sped up initiatives by developing a series of data-wrangling VBA macros for Excel.

#### Full-stack Developer

Vision Critical (now Alida) 🗷

04/2012 - 07/2014 Toronto, ON

Alida is a SaaS platform the world's largest brands use to build communities of customers for real-time feedback.

- Responsible for helping clients get the most out of the VC platform by customizing the functionality and workflows of their online market research surveys.
- On the front-end I used Web fundamental technologies (HTML, CSS, JavaScript including jQuery) to enhance and build upon the survey's default UI.
- On the back-end I used the platform's API (C#) to programmatically meet clients' complex serverside business logic including implementing segmentation and conjoint analysis algorithms.
- Successfully developed and deployed over 100+ high profile online surveys to 300,000+ users.

## **LANGUAGES / TECHNOLOGIES**





#### **EDUCATION**

#### **MBA**

Schulich School of Business

Toronto, ON

## Post-grad. Certificate, **Application Development** Conestoga College

Kitchener, ON

 Networks, Systems Design, SQL Database Management, Programming in C#, Web Fundamentals.

## **BA, Economics**

Wilfrid Laurier

Waterloo, ON



## **PROJECTS**

santidev.com 🗗

For additional information and more projects.

 A full-stack learning project for real-time, 1 on 1 chats. TypeScript, React, Redux, Express, PostgreSQL, TypeORM, Socket.IO, MUI

Colombia 1000 ♂

A front-end learning project in TypeScript and React (MUI) that consumes the Socrata REST API and displays Colombia's 1000 largest companies by revenue. Allows for searching by name and filtering by



## **LANGUAGES**

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Spanish

Native or Bilingual Proficiency



## **SOFT SKILLS**

Self-starter